Irving Fine Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Irving Fine Collection1930-1993 (bulk 1950-1962)
ML31.F5
Fine, Irving, 1914-1962
around 4,350 items 21 boxes 7 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The bulk of the materials in the collection are musical scores and sketches which represent virtually the entire musical output of the composer, some of which have been cataloged individually and classified and shelved in ML96.F47, ML96.5.F47, ML30.3C.F55, and ML29c.F527. In addition there are photographs, clippings, programs, scrapbooks, as well as correspondence from 20th century musicians such as Leonard Bernstein, Aaron Copland, Lukas Foss, Alberto Ginastera, Ned Rorem, and William Schuman.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990--Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Fine, Irving, 1914-1962--Autographs.; Fine, Irving, 1914-1962--Correspondence.; Fine, Irving, 1914-1962.; Fine, Irving, 1914-1962.; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009--Correspondence.; Ginastera, Alberto, 1916-1983--Correspondence.; Rorem, Ned, 1923- --Correspondence.; Schuman, William, 1910-1992--Correspondence.
Subjects
Composers--Correspondence.; Musicians--Portraits.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gifts, Verna Fine, 1964-1991.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Forty unpublished tapes transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division.
Access and Restrictions
The Irving Fine Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use. Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Alternate Format Available
Digitized images along with identifying information and a narrative introduction are also available through the Library of Congress Web site under the title: The Irving Fine collection, ca. 1914-1962, at http://memory.loc.gov/ammem/collections/fine/. The site was produced for the National Digital Library Program, American Memory collections.
Biographical Note
Irving Fine, American composer, teacher, and conductor, was born in Boston, Massachusetts, on December 3, 1914. He received both his bachelor's (1937) and his master's (1938) degrees from Harvard University, where he studied composition with Walter Piston and Edward Burlingame Hill. He studied composition, as well, with Nadia Boulanger in Cambridge, Massachusetts, and Paris, France, and pursued studies in choral conducting with A. T. Davison and orchestral conducting with Serge Koussevitzky. From 1939 until 1950, Fine taught at Harvard, after 1947 as assistant professor of music. Subsequently, until the end of his life, he was professor of music at Brandeis University, also serving there as chairman of the School of Creative Arts. In addition, during the summers from 1946 to 1957, Fine was on the composition faculty at the Berkshire Music Center at Tanglewood.
Irving Fine was the recipient of numerous awards, including two Guggenheim Fellowships and a Fulbright Research Fellowship for France. In addition to his composing and teaching, he wrote articles and reviews for Modern Music, Notes, Musical America, and the New York Times. He died of a heart attack in Boston on August 23, 1962.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the materials in the collection are musical scores and sketches representing virtually the entire musical output of the composer. Among these materials are manuscripts for Alice in Wonderland (1942); The Hour Glass (1949), a song cycle for unaccompanied chorus set to texts by Ben Jonson; Mutability, a song cycle for contralto and piano originally commissioned by the Creative Concerts Guild, Inc., in 1952; Serious Song (1955), for string orchestra; and Symphony 1962, which was performed by the Boston Symphony Orchestra shortly before Fine's death in 1962.
In addition to music manuscripts, the collection contains an assortment of photographs, clippings, programs, scrapbooks and correspondence from 20th century musicians such as Leonard Bernstein, Aaron Copland, Lukas Foss, Alberto Ginastera, Ned Rorem, William Schuman and others.
Forty unpublished tapes presented to the Library by Verna Fine in 1969 feature recordings of concert, broadcast, and private performances of the composer's works. Fine himself is the piano accompanist for a number of songs, including the cycles Mutability and Childhood Fables for Grownups. These materials are in the custody of the Motion Picture, Broadcast and Recorded Sound Division of the Library of Congress. An inventory is included on file.
Robert Saladini, 1996
Organization of the Irving Fine Collection
The Irving Fine Collection is organized in 8 series:
Music
Writings
Correspondence
Photographs
Programs
Clippings
Scrapbooks
Printed Matter
http://lccn.loc.gov/2003561019
Container List
- Music (Box 1-4, Box 16)
  The Music series represents three subseries. The first subseries, Music Composed by Irving Fine, consists of manuscript and printed scores, and sketches. The second, Sketchbooks of Irving Fine, consists of 18 sketchbooks. The third series, Music by Others, consists of manuscript and printed scores.
  Music series is arranged into three subseries: Music Composed by Irving Fine, Sketchbooks of Irving Fine, and Music by Others. The sketchbooks are arranged by number and housed in box 4. The other subseries are arranged by composer and title.
  - Music by Irving Fine (Box 1-2a)
    - After Stravinsky, Ms. parts in ink for piccolo, horn, trumpet, and violin (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Three choruses from Alice in Wonderland [1942], Ms. score (transparency) for chorus and piano (SATB); 21 p.; Ozalid score for chorus and piano (SATB); 21 p.; Contents: Lobster quadrille Lullaby of the duchess Father William (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Father William See also: It's the navy, the navy!, Score (negative) for voice and piano; [2] p.; Note: variant version; Uniform title: Three choruses from Alice in Wonderland (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Father William See also: It's the navy, the navy!, Score (copy) for men's chorus (TTBB); [4] p.; Uniform title: Three choruses from Alice in Wonderland (Box-folder 1/2)
    - [Three choruses from Alice in Wonderland (1953)], Holograph score (transparency) for women's chorus and piano; [19] p.; Ozalid holograph score for women's chorus and piano; [19] p.; On cover of "Beautiful soup" and "The white knight's song": "Composed for the one hundred and fiftieth anniversary of the founding of Bradford Junior College"; Contents: The knave's letter The white knight's song Beautiful soup (Box-folder 1/3)
    - The white knight's song, Score (negative) for voice and piano; [3] p.; Note: dated 1943; Uniform title: Three choruses from Alice in Wonderland (Box-folder 1/3)
    - [Alice in wonderland suite (Diversions)], Holograph score (copy and negative) for piano; [4] p.; At top: "Music for Caucus race p. 13 and for running p. 79." (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Alice in Wonderland suite (1949), Ozalid holograph full score (chorus and orchestra), annotated; 47 p. (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Arioso, Holograph sketch in pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 1/5)
    - [Ballet, early (1940-41)], Holograph score for piano; [3] p. (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Blue-White (Brandeis University marching song), Holograph full score (transparency); 27 p.; Ozalid holograph full score, annotated; 27 p. (3 copies); Note: one copy retitled "Blue towers"; Uniform title: The blue and the white (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Blue towers see: The blue and the white
    - Childhood fables for grownups, Holograph piano-vocal score (medium voice) on transparency; 17 p.; Note: holograph score dated Jan. 1955; Ozalid holograph piano-vocal score; 17 p. (2 copies); Includes: Holograph sketch material (2 p.) and lyric sheet (2 p.) for "Four little mice"; Contents: Polaroli Tigeroo Lenny the leopard The frog and the snake (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Childhood fables for grownups, Holograph piano-vocal scores (4); 7 p; [7] p.; 8 p.; 10 p.; Note: holograph piano-vocal scores include 2 versions of "The duck and the yak"; Ozalid holograph piano-vocal scores (8); 7 p.; 10 p.; Typescript lyric sheets (7), some annotated.; Contents: Two worms The duck and the yak (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Four children's songs for grown-ups, [and], The duck and the yak, Bound holograph piano-vocal scores (photocopy and negative); [25] p.; Contents: Tigaroo Lenny the leopard Polaroli The frog and the snake The duck and the yak; Uniform title: Childhood fables for grownups (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Ching-a-ring chaw (Minstrel song), Ozalid score for chorus (SATB), annotated; 6 p.; Note: arranged by Irving Fine (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Ching-a-ring chaw (Minstrel song), Ozalid score for women's chorus (SSAA); 3 p.; Note: arranged by Irving Fine (Box-folder 2/1)
    - [Concerto, violin], Holograph sketch material; [4] p. (Box-folder 2/2)
    - [Concerto, violin], Holograph sketches in pencil; [12] p.; On folder: "tentatively identified by Verna Fine" (Box-folder 2/3)
    - [Concerto, violin], Holograph sketches; [17] p. (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Flamingo dance, Holograph full score; 10 p. (Box-folder 2/5)
    - For Claudia, Holograph score (transparency) for piano; 3 p.; Includes: Ozalid score (2) for piano; 3 p.; Includes: Score (photocopy) for "Lullaby for a baby panda"; 1 p. (incomplete); Contents: Lullaby for a baby panda Victory march of the elephants (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Four beasts, Holograph sketch for voice, cello, and clarinet (incomplete); [1] p.; Includes: unidentified holograph sketch for voice and piano (incomplete); [1] p. (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Fugue in F minor, Holograph score for 4 unidentified instruments; 6 p.; Note: dated June 1, 1938 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Fugue in F minor, Holograph score (incomplete); [4] p. (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Homage รก Mozart (1756-1956), Holograph score (transparency) for piano; 3 p.; Ozalid holograph score (2) for piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 2/9)
    - The hour glass: a cycle of songs for a capella chorus and solo voices, Ozalid holograph score, annotated; 32 p.; Contents: O know to end as to begin Have you seen the white lily grow O do not wanton with those eyes Against jealousy Lament The hour glass (Box-folder 2/10)
    - I don't have to hear music (This is heaven), Holograph score (photocopy and 2 negatives) for voice and piano; [2] p.; Note: dated 1942; Includes: Typescript correspondence to Maynard Kaplan from Paul Mills, American Academy of Music, Inc.; [1] p.; Includes: Holograph lyric sheet; Words by Maynard Kaplan (Box-folder 2/11)
    - I don't have to hear music (This is heaven), Holograph sketch fragment; [1] p.; Includes: Typescript correspondence to Maynard Kaplan from Paul Mills, American Academy of Music, Inc.; [1] p.; Includes: Holograph lyric sheet; Words by Maynard Kaplan (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Hymn, Ozalid holograph full score for women's chorus and small orchestra; 19 p.; At top: "For Serge Koussevitzky: In grato jubilo"; At end: Cambridge, Mass., 4/7/49; Uniform title: In grato jubilo (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Intermezzo for small orchestra, Holograph sketches; [10] p. (Box-folder 2/12)
    - It's funny, honey, Holograph score for piano with interpolated words; [3] p.; Typescript lyric sheet with pencil annotations (Box-folder 2/13)
    - It's the navy, the navy!, Holograph score for voice and piano; [2] p.; At top: "To Lt. George M. Powers U.S.N.R."; Holograph vocal part in pencil; [1] p.; Typescript lyric sheet, annotated; 2 p.; Note: slight modification of "Father William" from Three choruses from Alice in Wonderland (1942) (Box-folder 2/14)
    - A kiss from Mr. Liszt, Holograph score for voice and piano; [3] p.; Note: score dated 1942; Ms. lyric sheets with musical annotations; [5] p. (Box-folder 2/15)
    - A kiss from Mr. Liszt, Holograph score (photocopy and negative) for voice and piano (incomplete); [2] p. (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Leporello's song, Holograph lead sheet sketch; [2] p.; Holograph sketch material, including unrelated material; [2] p. (Box-folder 2/16)
    - A letter from Paris, Holograph score (and 2 negatives) for voice and piano; [2] p.; Holograph sketch; [6] p.; Ms. lyric sheet; [2] p.; Laid in: Typescript photocopy of correspondence from Paul Mills (American Academy of Music, Inc.) to Maynard Kaplan. (Box-folder 2/17)
    - ["Lonely little heart" f.l.], Holograph lead sheet; [2] p. (Box-folder 2/18)
    - [Maggie], Holograph sketch material; [2] p.; Ozalid condensed score (musical play/opera) of "Tell it to the worms"; 17 p. (2 copies); Ozalid condensed score (musical play/opera) of "I wonder"; 9 p. (3 copies); Laid in materials: players list; production budget sheets; play synopses; planning notes; correspondence (3); lyric sheets (17 p.); Note: collaborative work with Richard Wernick (Box-folder 2/19)
    - McCord's menagerie, Holograph scores for men's chorus (TBB); [10] p.; Contents: Vultur gryphus Jerboa Mole (Box-folder 2/20)
    - McCord's menagerie, Scores (4 photocopies, incomplete) for men's chorus (TBB); [8] p. each.; Note: Vultur gryphus and Jerboa, 1 copy; Mole and Clam, 3 copies.; Note: dedicated to the Harvard Glee club on its 100th anniversary; Contents: Vultur gryphus Jerboa Mole Clam, or, Whose ooze (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Measuring music, Holograph full score; 10 p. (Box-folder 2/21)
    - The Mesabi blues, Holograph unaccompanied song; [2] p.; On cover: "A Father's Day greeting to Papa Georgie - June 19, 1955, from Claudia, Emily, Joanna, Verna and Irving"; Lyrics by Irving Fine and Papa Georgie Fine (Box-folder 2a/1)
    - Music for piano, Ozalid holograph score for piano; 20 p.; Note: dated 1947; Contents: Prelude Waltz-Gavotte Variations Interlude and finale (Box-folder 15/5)
    - My name is Mussolini, Holograph score for voice and piano; [3] p.; Note: dated 1942.; Ms. lyric sheet; [2] p. (Box-folder 2a/2)
    - O Traurigkeit, Holograph score for organ; [1] p. (Box-folder 2a/4)
    - [Old concerto in manner of Stravinsky-Bach], Holograph sketches in pencil (fragile); [7] p.; At top: "Concerto - slow movt" (Box-folder 2a/5)
    - An old song, Ozalid holograph score, for chorus (3 copies, one annotated); 5 p. (Box-folder 2a/6)
    - Orchestral preludes, Holograph sketch/short score (photocopy); [14] p. (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Romanza for wind quintet, Ozalid holograph score (2); 32 p.; At top: "To Verna"; At top: "Commissioned by the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Foundation"; Ozalid parts (Box-folder 2a/7)
    - Romanza for wind quintet, Holograph sketches; [3] p. (Box-folder 2a/7)
    - [Serious song], Holograph sketch (incomplete); [2] p.; Note: early orchestra version (Box-folder 2a/8)
    - [Shepherd's song], Holograph sketches (fragile); [4] p. (Box-folder 2a/9)
    - [Sonata, cello], Holograph sketch score for cello and piano; [13] p.; On folder: early 1939 (Box-folder 2a/10)
    - [Sonata, violin and piano], Holograph sketch score for violin and piano; [16] p.; On folder: early (Box-folder 2a/11)
    - Song of the flowers, Ozalid ms. score for voice and piano; 7 p. (Box-folder 2a/12)
    - Springtime is ringtime, Holograph score for voice and piano (incomplete); [2] p. (Box-folder 2a/13)
    - Springtime is ringtime, Holograph sketches; [8] p.; Ms. lyric sheet (Box-folder 2a/13)
    - String quartet, Holograph sketch score; [40] p.; On title page: "Commissioned by the Koussevitzky Foundation and dedicated to the memory of Serge and Natalie Koussevitzky" (Box-folder 2a/14)
    - String quartet, Holograph 12-tone row elaborations; [1] p.; Includes: excerpts from ms. score (on transparency); [3] p. (Box-folder 2a/14)
    - String quartet, Ozalid holograph score; 52 p.; Note: dated Sept. 1951 - May 1952 (Box-folder 2a/14)
    - Suite for brass instruments, Holograph full score (incomplete); [2] p. (Box-folder 2a/15)
    - Symphony 1962, Ozalid copyist's full score, annotated; 32 p., [49 p., 48 p.]; On cover of portfolio: "print from original masters of Symphony (1962) with corrections for publication" (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Symphony 1962, Holograph score (photocopy) of different version; 28 p. (Box-folder 15/7)
    - There'll come a day, Holograph score for voice and piano, annotated; [2] p.; Note: dated 1942; Words by Michael Lynde (Box-folder 2a/16)
    - There'll come a day, Holograph score (negative) for voice and piano; [2] p.; Words by Michael Lynde (Box-folder 2a/16)
    - Waltz, Holograph score (incomplete); [1] p. (Box-folder 2a/17)
    - What is this warm feeling?, Holograph score for voice and piano; [2] p.; Note: dated 1942 (Box-folder 2a/18)
    - What is this warm feeling?, Holograph sketches; [3] p.; Ms. lyric sheet sketches; [3] p.; Words by Maynard Kaplan (Box-folder 2a/18)
    - [When men of war roll ashore in Cambridge Town], Holograph sketches for voice and piano (incomplete); [8] p. (Box-folder 2a/19)
    - Miscellaneous lyrics and sketch material, Holograph lyrics and sketches; [14] leaves; Includes: envelope; song list (mostly from World War II); expense sheet (Box-folder 2a/20)
    - Miscellaneous student music workbook, Bound holograph harmony and counterpoint exercises; [26] p.; On cover: "Irving G. Fine, Dunster J-35, Harvard College" (Box-folder 2a/21)
    - [Unidentified material], Holograph sketches; [54] p.; Contents: Holograph 4-part sketch score for an early orchestral work; [6] p. (BOX: 2a/22) Holograph score (incomplete) for piano; [2] p. (BOX: 2a/23) Holograph score for piano ("for Prof. Piston"); [2] p. (BOX: 2a/24) Holograph sketch score for violin, piano, cello; [7] p. (BOX: 2a/25) Holograph sketches; [5] leaves (BOX: 2a/26) Holograph sketches; [14] p. (BOX: 2a/27) Holograph sketches; [28] p. (BOX: 15/8) (Box-folder 2a/22-27, Box-folder 15/8)
  - Sketchbooks of Irving Fine (Box 4)
    - Sketchbook #1, Contains miscellaneous pencil sketches; Laid in: typed Old Testament verses (5 p.) and pencil sketches (5 p.) (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Sketchbook #2, Carl Fischer Spiral Music Writing Book; Quartet sketches; Contains text of Ben Jonson's "O know to end as to begin," used by Fine in the Hour glass, and misc. pencil sketches (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Sketchbook #3, Schirmer's Wire Bound Music Writing Book; Florida sketches; Contains misc. holograph pencil sketches with 6 p. laid in; Includes: "My little salamander" (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Sketchbook #4, Carl Fischer Spiral Music Writing Book; Contains 3 p. unidentified pencil sketches (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Sketchbook #5, Pheasant Music Book; Sketches for woodwind partita and string quartet (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Sketchbook #6, The Spiral Music; Contains holograph harmony exercises in pencil, 31 p. laid in (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Sketchbook #7, The Spiral Music; Contains unidentified pencil sketches; [6] p. (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Sketchbook #8, Boston Music Co. Series of Manuscript Books; Contains unidentified pencil sketches (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Sketchbook #9, Carl Fischer Spiral Music Writing Book; Orchestral piece, tone row and transformations; 1 p. laid in (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Sketchbook #10, Pheasant Music Book; Contains pencil sketches, mostly unidentified except for "Sad Sack at the U. S. O." and ["Choral New Yorker"] (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Sketchbook #11, Composer's Manuscript Tablet; Contains mostly counterpoint exercises in score (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Sketchbook #12, The Spiral Music; Contains 3 p. of pencil sketches, consisting of a tone row very similar to that in Sketchbook #9; 8 p. laid in (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Sketchbook #13, Schirmer's Spiral Music Writing Book; Contains unidentified pencil sketches (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Sketchbook #14, The Spiral Music; Contains unidentified pencil sketches; [4] p. (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Sketchbook #15, Champion music book; Contains unidentified pencil sketches; [21] p. (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Sketchbook #16, France; Contains pencil sketches, including some for a violin sonata (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Sketchbook #17, Perfect Riter Music Book; Contains unidentified sketches in pencil and ink (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Sketchbook #18, Champion music book; Holograph sketches in pencil; Includes dream description, [4] p. (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Music by Others (Box 3, Box 16)
    - Ballantine, Edward
      - Early in the morning and other pieces, for pianoforte. Boston: Arthur P. Schmidt Co., 1947., Note: inscribed by the composer. (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Variations for piano on Mary had a little lamb (2nd series). Boston: Arthur P. Schmidt Co., 1943., Note: inscribed by the composer.; 2nd series (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Berger, Arthur
      - Three bagatelles [for piano]. New York: Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1948., On title page: "For Irving--recalling old friendship that endures. Arthur. Jan. 1948" (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Boulanger, Nadia
      - Harmony course, Harmony/figured bass exercies (copy of ms.); 2 bks [8 p.; 10 p.] (Box-folder 2a/3)
    - Briggs, Mary
      - Sonata for flute and piano, Ozalid ms. score, annotated; 19 p.; At top: "To Irving & Verna for multiple kindnesses"; At end: December 1947, Cambridge, Mass.; Includes: Ozalid of ms. flute part (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Cazden, Norman
      - Passacaglia for piano, opus 46 (1944), Ozalid ms. score; [7] p.; On cover: "for Irving Fine"; Note: signed by composer (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Diamond, David
      - Timon of Athens: a symphonic portrait after Shakespeare. New York: Leeds Music Corporation, 1950., Note: study score; On title page: "for Verna & Irving, with much affection, David, July 31, 1950, Tanglewood." (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Gottlieb, Jack
      - Songs of loneliness, on seven poems by Constantine Cavafy (1962), Ozalid ms. score for voice and piano; 36 p.; Note: dedicated to Irving Fine (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Haieff, Alexei
      - Saints' wheel: variations on a circle of fifths, for piano (1960), Ozalid holograph score; 6 p.; On cover: "To my dear Irving with love, admiration and a 'prehistoric' friendship, Alexei, NY, Dec. 1960"; Note: commissioned by the Naumburg Foundation (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Jones, Collier
      - Sonata for piano (1956), Ozalid ms. score; 14 p.; Laid in: ms. letter to Irving Fine from Collier (Charlie) Jones; Inscribed by the composer (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Kohn, Karl
      - Five pieces for piano (1955), Ozalid copyist's score; [18] p.; At top: "for Irving, with best wishes, from Karl" (Box-folder 3/9)
      - Sonatina for piano (1950), Ozalid copyist's score; 11 p.; At top: "for my friend and teacher Irving Fine, from Karl Kohn" (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Lukewitz, Joseph
      - Poems by a little girl, for mixed chorus a capella (1959), Ozalid copyist's score; [26] p.; At top: "To Irving Fine--in friendship, Joseph Lukewitz, Feb. 1960" (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Orgad, Ben-Zion
      - Out of the dust: three songs by Er'ela Ur (1960), Ozalid copyist's score for mezzo-soprano or alto, flute, bassoon, viola, and violoncello; [45] p.; On title page: "To Prof. Fine, with many thanks and admiration, Ben-Zion Orgad, Brandeis 1961" (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Piston, Walter
      - Passacaglia [for piano]. New York: Mercury Music Corporation, 1943., Note: inscribed by the composer. (Box-folder 3/12)
      - Prelude and allegro, for organ and strings. New York: Arrow Music Press, Inc., 1944., Note: inscribed by the composer. (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Read, Gardner
      - Passacaglia and fugue, in D minor, for organ, op. 34. Boston: R.D. Row Music Company, 1937., On title page: "To Irving and Verna, with warmest good wishes, Gardner Read, 9/15/47" (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Salas, Juan Orrego